<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-18T20:13:54-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Whiskey Bob</title><subtitle>Writing about whiskey every day.
</subtitle><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><entry><title type="html">Kickin’ in Kildalton - Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/18/kildalton-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kickin' in Kildalton - Part 2" /><published>2018-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/18/kildalton-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/18/kildalton-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s revisit the Laphroaig 10 alongside the Ardbeg 10. I poured 15 mL neat of each in Glencairns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;laphroaig-10&quot;&gt;Laphroaig 10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Color: Much darker than the Ardbeg. It’s artificial.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: Peat smoke, medicinal notes, salty seaside notes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste: Hits softer than the Ardbeg. Takes time to develop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: More of the seaside brininess comes out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ardbeg-10&quot;&gt;Ardbeg 10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Color: Much lighter than the Laphroaig. I assume it’s natural.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: Peat smoke, some sort of light citrusy sweetness. Less complex than the Laphroaig&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste: Ashy smoke hits right away. Much stronger than the Laphroaig.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: Long, deep finish. Packs a punch. Less going on but more to my tastes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I drink other Islays, the more I appreciate the subtleties of the Laphroaig. That said, I prefer the favor profile of the Ardbeg. But these are both mighty fine expressions and the “better” one comes down to personal preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be back tomorrow to compare the three together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whisky Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Scotch" /><category term="Islay" /><category term="Ardbeg 10" /><category term="Laphroaig 10" /><summary type="html">Let’s revisit the Laphroaig 10 alongside the Ardbeg 10. I poured 15 mL neat of each in Glencairns.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kickin’ in Kildalton - Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/17/kildalton-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kickin' in Kildalton - Part 1" /><published>2018-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/17/kildalton-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/17/kildalton-1.html">&lt;p&gt;I spent the day snowtubing with Whiskey Kid #1. We were just a few minutes away from a New Hampshire liquor barn and she graciously agreed to a quick trip. Fortunately for her, I had my shopping list ready and it was a quick trip. I picked up enough to fill out my 8 month plan (with one summer exception) and bring my yearly total up to ~$700. I’ve got too much whisky stock… better drink some of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was to continue on with my Speyside tastings but I feel like a need a quick return to something I know before going back for further evaluation. That, and my most cherished acquisition today was the Ardbeg Explorer’s pack for $48. This includes a 750 mL bottle of the standard Ardbeg 10 and 50 mL samplers of Uigeadail and Corryvreckan. This has to be the best value that I’ve yet come across. Thanks, New Hampshire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ardbeg-exploration.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of Ardbeg Exploration Pack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I return to Islay, my whisky home. I’m calling this sojourn “Kickin’ in Kildalton” as I now possess the three standard expressions from the Kildalton distilleries on the south of Islay - Lagavulin 16, Laphroaig 10 and now Ardbeg 10. I’ll kick it off today by comparing Ardbeg 10 and Lagavulin 16. We’re going just taste today and will get into more details over the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lagavulin-16&quot;&gt;Lagavulin 16&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the expression I’m most familiar with. The 15 mL neat pour today is the same as the last time I had it - peaty, smoky, medicinal, complex finish. I’m getting more bitter notes than ever before through this comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ardbeg-10&quot;&gt;Ardbeg 10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, standard Ardbeg. What you got?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: Peat smoke, similar to the Lagavulin. Some light citrus notes underneath the smoke. Not quite as medicinal as the Lagavulin. The smoke seems a bit more intense.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste: Ashy in the back of my mouth as the whisky swirls around my tongue. Some numbing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: Yum, this is good. Very long. Some drying. More intense smoke than the Lagavulin. But also some lighter citrus notes like on the nose. Less complex than the Lagavulin but what’s here is incredibly pleasant. A sip can last minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow. OK. I’m an Ardbeg guy. I’m still a Lagavulin guy but the Ardbeg really impresses me. I can’t wait to do an Ardbeg vertical and compare the base expression with the Uigeadail and Corryvreckan. But first, we need to see how the Laphroiag holds up… tomorrow…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whisky Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Scotch" /><category term="Islay" /><category term="Ardbeg 10" /><category term="Lagavulin 16" /><summary type="html">I spent the day snowtubing with Whiskey Kid #1. We were just a few minutes away from a New Hampshire liquor barn and she graciously agreed to a quick trip. Fortunately for her, I had my shopping list ready and it was a quick trip. I picked up enough to fill out my 8 month plan (with one summer exception) and bring my yearly total up to ~$700. I’ve got too much whisky stock… better drink some of it!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accountability</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/16/accountability.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accountability" /><published>2018-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/16/accountability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/16/accountability.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get overly excited when jumping into a new hobby, especially one as delicious as whiskey. It can also be fiscally and physically dangerous when jumping into a new hobby, especially one as delicious as whiskey. Alcoholism is far too real and can capture anyone. I really want to keep this a fun and sustainable hobby. But just a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those reasons, I will take some planned days off of drinking here and there. One reason for this blog is to write every day so I’ll fill my #NoWhiskey days with accountability posts like this, book reviews, or boring history lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also keep a budget and share spending here. I’m choosing to share this info because 1. it helps keep me accountable and 2. it might be useful for readers to see prices and price out their own whiskey adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked the budget over with Mrs. Whiskey and we agreed on a target of $1200-$1500 for the year with a hard cap of $1825. These figures account for me giving up takeout coffee and less photography equipment in our overall budget. The lower end figure is based on $4/day with 300 days of drinking. The hard cap is based on $5/day drinking every day. While I won’t be drinking every day, the higher number gives me some flexibility to freely share samples with friends. This whole journey will be way more fun with friends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent about $500 year to date and have $200 ready to plop down at a New Hampshire liquor barn (live tax free or die, baby!). This inventory should set me up pretty well for the next 6-8 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These figures might seem extravagant to many or laughable to a few but it works for us. Hopefully the transparency is helpful, dear reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whiskey Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="NoWhiskey" /><summary type="html">It’s easy to get overly excited when jumping into a new hobby, especially one as delicious as whiskey. It can also be fiscally and physically dangerous when jumping into a new hobby, especially one as delicious as whiskey. Alcoholism is far too real and can capture anyone. I really want to keep this a fun and sustainable hobby. But just a hobby.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Spey, I Spey - Part 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/15/speyside-04.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Spey, I Spey - Part 4" /><published>2018-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/15/speyside-04</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/15/speyside-04.html">&lt;p&gt;Tearing into my final 50 mL Speyside sampler tonight, Speyburn 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: More complex than the Glens of yesterday. Alcohol burn right off the bat followed by grass and light fruit notes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste: Medium body. Lots of alcohol that burns away other flavors. Most of the taste is in the finish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: Huge alcohol hit at first followed by grassy sweetness. Some earthiness. Drying on the tongue that I didn’t notice until the second sip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot going on here and I’m not sure it all comes together. There are some nice flavors in here but also a huge alcohol burn. I think I’d take this over the boring Glens, however. At least there’s something going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be back tomorrow mixing up my Speyside pairings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whisky Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Scotch" /><category term="Speyside" /><category term="Speyburn 10" /><summary type="html">Tearing into my final 50 mL Speyside sampler tonight, Speyburn 10.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Spey, I Spey - Part 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/14/speyside-03.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Spey, I Spey - Part 3" /><published>2018-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/14/speyside-03</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/14/speyside-03.html">&lt;p&gt;Cracking open two more Speyside 50 mL samplers today - Glenlivet 12 and Glenfiddich 12. I get these confused all the time. I poured 15 mLs of each into Glencairns and promptly forgot which was which. This bodes well for the tasting…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to my usual taste first style, I’m going to grab the tasting notes from the respective websites to see if I can figure out which is which.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;glenlivet-12&quot;&gt;Glenlivet 12&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theglenlivet.com/en-us/the-glenlivet-12-year-old/&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;40% ABV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cask: Traditional and American oak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flavor: Delicately balanced with strong pineapple notes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Colour: Bright, vibrant gold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: Fruity and summery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Palate: Well balanced and fruity, with strong pineapple notes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: Creamy, smooth, with marzipan and fresh hazelnuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$5.29/50mL -&amp;gt; $1.59/15mL pour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;glenfiddich-12&quot;&gt;Glenfiddich 12&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glenfiddich.com/us/collection/product-collection/core-range/12-year-old/&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;40% ABV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fresh pear, subtle oak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$5.99/50mL -&amp;gt; $1.80/15mL pour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With a unique freshness from the same Highland spring water we’ve used since 1887, its distinctive fruitiness comes from the high cut point William Grant always insisted upon.
Carefully matured in the finest American oak and European oak sherry casks for at least 12 years, it is mellowed in oak marrying tuns to create its sweet and subtle oak flavours.
Creamy with a long, smooth and mellow finish, our 12 Year Old is the perfect example of Glenfiddich’s unique Speyside style and is widely proclaimed the best dram in the valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-take&quot;&gt;My take&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to pick out the “strong pineapple notes” but can’t find them. Both are light and fruity. One has a bit more woodiness and kick on the backend. That one might be the Glenfiddich with the “subtle oak” description. Neither one have a terribly long finish. These seem really interchangeable upon first taste. Maybe a couple more samplings will reveal more differences…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whisky Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Scotch" /><category term="Speyside" /><category term="Glenlivet 12" /><category term="Glenfiddich 12" /><summary type="html">Cracking open two more Speyside 50 mL samplers today - Glenlivet 12 and Glenfiddich 12. I get these confused all the time. I poured 15 mLs of each into Glencairns and promptly forgot which was which. This bodes well for the tasting…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Spey, I Spey - Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/13/speyside-02.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Spey, I Spey - Part 2" /><published>2018-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/13/speyside-02</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/13/speyside-02.html">&lt;p&gt;I lucked into 50 mL samples of &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; Macallan 12 Year Sherry Cask and 12 Year Double Cask. These are classy samplers that come with their own box. That’s probably why they cost so much more than the Jack samples I’ll get to when I venture stateside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a Macallan 12 sherry expression years ago and it didn’t leave much of an impression. I’m not looking at any tasting notes before trying these this time. All I know is that the “The” ahead of Macallan is stupid and I’m not going to write it any more. And that these are Speyside, keeping with my theme and going against my desire to drink Lagavulin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;macallan-12---sherry-cask&quot;&gt;Macallan 12 - Sherry Cask&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;43% ABV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matured in Sherry Oak casks from Jerez, Spain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$8.49/50mL -&amp;gt; $2.55/15mL pour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: more intense sherry than the Double Cask. It smells nice and sweet and rounded. Fruit notes along with some vanilla and wood notes. Nowhere near as intense as the A’bunadh yesterday. I detect more sherry the longer I sit with it and compare it to the Double Cask.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste: Nice and light in the mouth. Not much numbing. I get general sherry notes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: rather short. Mostly sherry notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;macallan-12---double-cask&quot;&gt;Macallan 12 - Double Cask&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;43% ABV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matured in Sherry seasoned American and European Oak casks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$8.99/50mL -&amp;gt; $2.70/15mL pour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: Smells about the same as the sherry version, just a little less intense. I get a bit more darker woody notes after letting it sit a bit. i&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste: There’s more going on here than the Sherry version. More woodiness with some sherry undertones. A bit more numbing. I detect more wood the longer I sit with it. There’s a bit more of an alcohol hit here than with the sherry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: The sherry comes out in a nice sweet finish. The finish is more memorable here - not sure if it actually lasts longer or if the reveal of sweetness adds a nice dimension to the dram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship between these two reminds me a lot of the relationship between Bushmills Original and Jameson standard - the bushmills was smoother and the Jameson had a bit more going on. Here, the sherry version is smoother and the Double Caks has a bit more going on. I preferred the Bushmills in the Irish comparison but this one is a bit more of a toss up. The sherry version is simpler but it’s really nice. I appreciate how a sip of the Double Cask evolves from vanilla/woody in the mouth to sherry in the finish. I think this choice depends on your mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whisky Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Scotch" /><category term="Speyside" /><category term="Macallan 12" /><category term="Macallan Double Cask 12" /><summary type="html">I lucked into 50 mL samples of The Macallan 12 Year Sherry Cask and 12 Year Double Cask. These are classy samplers that come with their own box. That’s probably why they cost so much more than the Jack samples I’ll get to when I venture stateside.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Spey, I Spey - Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/12/speyside-01.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Spey, I Spey - Part 1" /><published>2018-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/12/speyside-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/12/speyside-01.html">&lt;p&gt;Speyside has the largest concentration of Scotland’s distillers and seems to have just as many styles. I was fortunate enough to grab a good deal on one famous bottle and pickup a handful of Speyside samplers. This should keep me busy for a couple weeks. First up, that famous bottle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aberlour-abunadh&quot;&gt;Aberlour A’bunadh&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Batch #60&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;60.3% ABV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paid $70 for 750 mL bottle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prorated to $2.33/25mL, $1.40/15mL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aberlour.com/us/range/aberlour-abunadh/&quot;&gt;Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matured exclusively in Oloroso sherry casks. Bottled at cask strength&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scotch has held an almost mystical place in my mind since starting this whisky journey. Years ago a buddy described it as the best scotch he ever had. The name is strange and foreign and conjures an image of exotic flavors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is it in reality? I poured a nice 25 mL portion neat into a Glencairn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Color: The reddest whisky I’ve yet encountered. Not sure if it’s natural
Nose: Holy cherry and alcohol, Batman! It took a few sniffs to get through the 60% alcohol but then a wonderful dark red stone fruit aroma came to the front. There’s a lot more going on here but I can’t quite make it out yet.
Taste: This is thick. I get an explosion of fruit flavors. The high alcohol content numbs as I swish it through my mouth.
Finish: Dry, cherry candy. Hot damn! This tastes just like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Haribo-Gummi-Candy-Happy-Cherries/dp/B000EVT04M?th=1&quot;&gt;Haribo Twin Cherries&lt;/a&gt;. There’s an intial unpleasant waxiness to the finish that goes away after a couple more sips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one big bold sherry bomb. It’s the complete opposite of the smoky, complex Lagavulin. I drink whisky to experience new things like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water helps open up some more flavors but I can’t quite wrap my head around it all just yet. Good thing there’s almost a full bottle left to explore…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whisky Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Scotch" /><category term="Speyside" /><category term="Aberlour A'bunadh 60" /><summary type="html">Speyside has the largest concentration of Scotland’s distillers and seems to have just as many styles. I was fortunate enough to grab a good deal on one famous bottle and pickup a handful of Speyside samplers. This should keep me busy for a couple weeks. First up, that famous bottle:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sampling Ireland - Part 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/11/ireland-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sampling Ireland - Part 5" /><published>2018-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/11/ireland-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/11/ireland-5.html">&lt;p&gt;Time to wrap up this sampling of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tullamore-dew&quot;&gt;Tullamore D.E.W.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was by far my least favorite the first time around. It tasted like feet. I’ll be trying it solo first and then later on alongside Redbreast 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: There’s an unpleasant earthiness at first that gives way to the Irish “buttery” notes with a nice extra dose of honey. The earthiness grows on me as I sit with this dram. I still find it unpleasant but can just as easily see someone else calling it out as a favorite note.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste: Better than the other day. Less earth than before. More honey, some ginger. Not a ton going on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: Fairly short. A little alcohol burn. Some citrusy honey flavors linger. Not bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compared-to-redbreast-12&quot;&gt;Compared to Redbreast 12&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tullamore stood up surprisingly well this time around. It still tastes like dirt, but in a better way. There’s a bit too much bitterness on the finish and I’d say it’s still probably the least favorite of all sampled. But it’s not terrible dirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how much else I can say about the Redbreast 12 at this point. It’s quintessential Irish with a nice complexity. I pick some some excessive alcohol burn here and there that knocks it down a bit. Overall, this is lovely stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a map of the Irish expressions I sampled (Hopefully I can revise this soon to include links to blog posts):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/2/embed?mid=1bDD0xVYA7KYxDUcrU4PSiY6EUk4fVftg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redbreast 12 - Quintessential Irish butter and honey biscuit. Complex and full of character with maybe a tad too much alcohol burn. &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bushmill’s Original - Butter and honey and ginger. Not complex but smooth. &lt;strong&gt;B-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jamesons - Redbreast without the complexity. &lt;strong&gt;C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tullamore D.E.W. - Butter and honey and dirt. Not sure if I like the dirt. &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I enjoyed my trip to Ireland but am ready to sample from another region. Next time I’m back around these parts, I hope to try out a few other expressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green Spot - can’t wait to experience that magical “coconut” note&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connemara - a peated Irish whiskey? I’m in!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Powers - a competitor at the Bushmills/Jameson/Tullamore level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where will this magical whiskey tour go next? Tune in tomorrow to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whiskey Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Irish" /><category term="Tullamore DEW" /><category term="Redbreast 12" /><summary type="html">Time to wrap up this sampling of Ireland.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sampling Ireland - Part 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/10/ireland-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sampling Ireland - Part 4" /><published>2018-02-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/10/ireland-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/10/ireland-4.html">&lt;p&gt;I have a number of guiding principles in undertaking this whiskey quest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gain a deeper appreciation for all styles of whisk(e)y&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write every day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never use terminology I don’t understand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn from others and expand my terminology after my initial impression&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drink every day with rare exception&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stick to 30 - 50 mL intake every day with rare exception&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stick with my current drinking plan (even when I just want to drink Lagavulin)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address point 7, yes, I really want some Lagavulin… but it’s time to finish up this tiny bottle of Jameson. I’m going to drink it tonight along with its Midleton distillery stablemate Redbreast 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address points 3 and 4, I’ve formed my initial impressions over the last few days. There is some common something-or-other that links all these Irish whiskeys together but I can’t quite describe it. Fortunately, the magnificent bastards over at the Whiskey Vault are here to help:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I6stmin_260&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize their notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;redbreast-12&quot;&gt;Redbreast 12&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They call this the quintessential Irish whiskey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: Butter with honey like a biscuit (I feel you, Rex). Daniel calls this out as the classical note you’ll experience with evenry Irish whiskey distilled with the single pot still process. The process uses a mix of malted and unmalted barley.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This expression was finished in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oloroso&quot;&gt;Oloroso sherry casks&lt;/a&gt; that impart some darker fruit notes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rex: “This reminds me of a more complex Jameson”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rex thinks this is better than Green Spot. Daniel thinks Green Spot is better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jameson&quot;&gt;Jameson&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harsher on the nose but with green apples. Spice and bright and flashy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;green-spot-i-unfortunately-dont-have-any-to-compare&quot;&gt;Green Spot (I unfortunately don’t have any to compare)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brighter and lighter with saltwater and coconut&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daniel: “Magical coconut note”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-revised-takes&quot;&gt;My revised takes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the honey butter biscuit note. That does a pretty good job of describing what I’ve experienced as the quintessential Irish flavor. It’s creamy and a little sweet and chewy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describing Redbreast 12 as a more complex Jameson matches up exactly with my initial impressions and I stick to it. I get a lot more alcohol burn from the Jameson despite them both being at 40% ABV. I’m not quite picking up the fruit notes they talk about in the Redbreast but detect an overall sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be back tomorrow to wrap up this short sampling of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whiskey Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Irish" /><category term="Jameson" /><category term="Redbreast 12" /><summary type="html">I have a number of guiding principles in undertaking this whiskey quest:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sampling Ireland - Part 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/09/ireland-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sampling Ireland - Part 3" /><published>2018-02-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/09/ireland-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/02/09/ireland-3.html">&lt;p&gt;Despite a desire to drink Lagavulin, I’m going to stick it out and continue with my Irish samples. I’m revisiting the 50 mL samples of Bushmills Original and Jameson standard. I prefered the Bushmills on the first sampling - I liked its smoother taste and gingery finish. How do these hold up on second tasting?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I poured both neat into Glencairns. I finished up the Bushmills and have a bit of the Jameson left over to compare with its stablemate Redbreast tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bushmills-original&quot;&gt;Bushmills Original&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Color: Light apple juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: Light and fruity. A bit of alcohol burn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste: Light and fruity. Thinnish mouth feel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: Medium length citrus and ginger-like spice. Nice fruit notes that stick with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jameson&quot;&gt;Jameson&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Color: Darker fancy apple juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nose: A bit darker fruit and more complex than the Bushmills. Some earthy tones. Like apple juice that’s sat out in the sun a bit too long but not necessarily in a bad way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taste: Apples, earth, a bit of alcohol kick. Slightly thicker.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish: More intense flavors than the Bushmills. This seems like a less complex version of the Redbreast 12.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tjVzGYZLhvo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, McNulty, I am Protestant, and I favor the Bushmills. While this second round with the Jameson is much better than the first, the lightness of the Bushmills is more of what I’m looking for in this style. I can appreciate why one would prefer the complexity of the Jameson if one were to have to choose… but I’ll take the simple sweet here and save the complexity for other styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whiskey Bob signing off.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Whiskey Bob</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Irish" /><category term="Bushmills Original" /><category term="Jameson" /><summary type="html">Despite a desire to drink Lagavulin, I’m going to stick it out and continue with my Irish samples. I’m revisiting the 50 mL samples of Bushmills Original and Jameson standard. I prefered the Bushmills on the first sampling - I liked its smoother taste and gingery finish. How do these hold up on second tasting?</summary></entry></feed>